Guide to the Division of Nutritional Sciences records,1947-2018.
Division of Nutritional Sciences records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Division of Nutritional Sciences records, 1947-2018.
29-1-3247
Division of Nutritional Sciences
17.1 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Printed Materials, Publications, Reports, Photographs, Financial Records, CDs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, reports, grants, course syllabi, meeting minutes, program files, awards, photographs, and department reviews concerning the Division.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, faculty annual reports (some on CDs), grants, course syllabi (on CDs), meeting minutes, program files, awards, photographs, department reviews concerning the Division, and material concerning the Cornell Food and Nutrition Policy Program (CFNPP).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Division of Nutritional Sciences; Cornell University--Curricula.; Cornell Food and Nutrition Policy Program.; Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program--(U.S.); New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Division of Nutritional Sciences.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Division of Nutritional Sciences.
Subjects:
Nutritional Sciences--Study and teaching.; Nutrition policy.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Compact discs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Additional material and digital versions can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/11733
RELATED MATERIAL
See also collections #21-24-3292, Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program Records; #21-24-1975, Cornell University Cooperative Extension Records; and #23-2-2817, Cornell University College of Human Ecology Records; #29-4-2733, Division of Nutritional Sciences Cooperative Extension Nutrition Program Records for related material.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Committees
Box 10- Folder: 1-16; Box 18- Folder: 7
Series II. Correspondence
Box 8- Folder: 8-34; Box 9- Folders: 1-32
Series III. Directories and Rosters
Box 1- Folder: 2
Series IV. Events and Visitors
Box 1- Folder: 15,20; Box 9- Folders: 33-34; Box 14- Folder :31
Series V. Facilities
Box 1- Folder: 15, 26-38; Box 11- Folders: 1
Series VI. Faculty and Course Syllabi
Box 7- Folder: 1-23; Box 13- Folders: 9
Series VII. Funding
Box 2- Folder: 20-47
Series VIII. Grants and Proposals
Box 5- Folder: 13-31; Box 6- Folders: 1-24
Series IX. Programs
Box 1; Box 3- Folder: 1-36; Box 4- Folders: 1-33; Box 5- Folders: 1-12; Box 11- Folders: 2-5; Box 18- Folder: 8; Box 22- Folder: 12
Series X. Publications
Box 1- Folder: 14, 16-17, 22; Box 13- Folders: 1-11; Box 18- Folders: 1-4
Series XI. Reports; Faculty Annual Reports
Box 1- Folder: 21; Box 10- Folders: 17-28; Box 14- Folders: 1-54; Box 15- Folders: 1-28; Box 18- Folder: 9; Box 22
Series XII. Reviews and Strategic Plans
Box 1- Folder: 1, 4-13, 24; Box 7- Folders: 24-32; Box 8- Folders: 1-7
Series XIII. Scholarships/Awards
Box 2- Folder: 1-19; Box 18- Folder: 10-26
Series XIV. University Concerns
Box 10- Folder: 29-35
Series XV. Photographs and Slides
Box 12- Folder: 1-31; Box 18- Folder: 5-6
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Committees
  - Committees in DNS, 1974-1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - DNS Committees, 1974-2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - DNS Committee Membership, 2002-2007 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Council, 1991-1994 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Affirmative Action Advisory Committee, 1990-1995 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Appointments and Tenure, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Curriculum Review, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Honors Program, 1984-1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - American Institute of Nutrition Education, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Report of DNS Planning Committee, 1987-02 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - DNS Planning, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - DNS Retreat, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Food and Nutrition Planning Council, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Food and Nutrition Planning Council, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Nutrition Intervention and Policy - Report, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Planning Committee for Spring Symposium, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Student Chapter: Society for Nutrition Education, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 54-56)
  - Committees, 1974-2010 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Field of Nutrition-Meeting Minutes (1983) and Report, 2005-2006 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Honors Committee, 1974-1995 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Safety Committee, 1983-1995 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Animal Facilities Committee, 1987-1991 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Committees- Extension, 1987-1993 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - DNS Research Committee, 1988-1995 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1989-1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Nutrition Intervention and Policy Committee, 1989-1991 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - International Development Studies Program Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Appointments and Tenure Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Nutrition as an Integrating Discipline (NID) Committee, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - External Advisory Board - Bios, 2014 (Box 20, Folder 19)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Anderson, Carol, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - David Call, 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - David Call, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - David Call, 1978-1982 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1992--03 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1993-03-1994-07 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1994-08-1993-12 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1996-01-1996-10 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1996-11-1998-01 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1998-01-1998-11 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - 1998-09 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - 1998-10 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - 1998-11 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - 1998-12 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Firebaugh, Francille, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Gates, Jeffrey, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Kendig, James, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence and Memos - Kinzelberg, 1992-1997 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Kinzelberg, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Dean Lund, 1996-08-1997-01 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Dean Lund, 1995-10-1996-07 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Dean Lund, 1997-02-1998-05 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - McClintock, Charles, 1990-1993-08 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - McClintock, Charles, 1993-09-1995-02 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - McClintock, Charles, 1995-02-1997 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Olson, Christine - Research and Graduate Studies, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Robinson, Jean, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Ziegler, Jeri, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Affairs and Development - CALS, 1990-1996 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - China, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Cooperative Extension, 1988-1996 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Cooperative Extension Budget, 1989-1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Computing and Statistical Consulting, 1990-1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Computing and Statistical Consulting, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and Memos - Cooperative Extension, 1996-2001 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - DNS Write-ups, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and Memos - Emeritus Professors, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Geneva Experiment Station, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Geneva Experiment Station, 1988-1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Geneva Experiment Station, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Geneva Experiment Station, 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Geneva Experiment Station, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Finance and Business Office, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Graduate School, 1990-1996 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Provost's Office, 1990-1996 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Vice President Research and Advanced Studies, 1989-1996 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - DNS Director Search, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Memos - College, 1992-1998 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - WFP (Catholic Relief Services), 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence with Government Representatives, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with Government Representatives, 1992-1995 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - CALS - General, 1992-1997 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - General, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Letters from Garza to Faculty in the College, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence and Memos - Visitors to DNS, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence and Memos - Visitors to DNS, 1990-1993 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence and Memos - Visitors to DNS, 1991-1994 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence and Memos - DNS Graduate Students, 1995-1996 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence concerning DNS Governance, 2009-2014 (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Series III. Directories and Rosters
  - Profiles of the Research Faculty, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Rosters of Academic Staff, 1993-1994, 1997-1998, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Inside Information (moved to web format), 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Inside Information (moved to web format), 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Inside Information (moved to web format), 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series IV. Events and Visitors
  - 10th Anniversary Event, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Division Creation Announcement, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Daphne Roe Symposium on Nutrition in Academics, Government and Industry, 1994-06-04 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences Graduation Programs, 2002, 2007, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences Graduation Programs, 2001, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Delegation from Wageningen Centre for Food Science - Visit, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Graduation, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Graduation Ceremony, 2006; DVD-2633
  - Graduation Ceremony Slide Show, 2007; DVD-2634
  - Graduation Ceremony, 2008; DVD-1937
  - Graduation - Photo Reflections, 2009; DVD-1938
  - Graduation Ceremony, 2009; DVD-1939
  - Graduation Student Speakers, 2011; DVD-1940
  - Graduation Faculty Speakers, 2011; DVD-1941
  - Graduation Ceremony, 2011; DVD-1942
  - Presentations given in the Division of Nutritional Sciences, 1995-2003 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Field of Nutrition Seminar, 2011-01-24; DVD-1945; Brannon, Patsy
  - DNS Commencement Address, 2012; Stover, Patrick (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Joyce Lindower Wolitzer and Steven Wolitzer Nutrition Seminar, 2012-02 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Joyce Lindower Wolitzer and Steven Wolitzer Nutrition Seminar, 2013-10-01; DVD-1181; Lempert, Phil (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Field of Nutrition Seminar Series, 2013-09-23; DVD-1180; Qian, Shu-Bing (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Speakers for Seminars, Symposiums, Lectureships, 2012-2013 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Dorothy Proud Lectureship, 2013-11; DVD-1943; Herrin, Maricia
  - Dorothy Proud Lectureship, 2016-04-13; DVD-1944; Mitchell, Faye Berger
  - Graduation Ceremony, 2014; DVD-2635
  - History of Human Biology, Health and Society (HBHS), 2014; CD-2225 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Obesity, from cosmetic issue, 2016-05-09; DVD-1946; Grave, Gilman
  - Obesity, from cosmetic issue, 2016-05-09; DVD-1947; Grave, Gilman
  - The Business of Nutrition, 2016-04-13; DVD-1948; Mitchell, Faye Berger
  - Mechanotransduction, 2016-05-02; DVD-1949; Hornberger, Troy
  - Mechanotransduction, 2016-05-02; DVD-1950; Hornberger, Troy
  - Unmasking the stories behind high folate, 2016-08-29; DVD-1951; Berry, R J
  - Unmasking the stories behind high folate, 2016-08-29; DVD-1952; Berry, R J
  - Applying Focus ethnographic methods, 2016-09-26; DVD-1953; Pelto, Gretel
  - Applying Focus ethnographic methods, 2016-09-26; DVD-1954; Pelto, Gretel
  - Growing Dignity and Resilience: Action research for food sovereignty with five communities in the US, 2016-09-29; DVD-1955; Porter, Christine
    International Nutrition Seminar
  - Lecture, 2014-03-27; DVD-1956; Pingali, Prabhu
  - Assessing Women's Time, 2016-10-05; DVD-1957; Matare, Cynthia
  - Evaluating the integration of nutrition-sensitive oFSP into ante-natal care services in Western Kenya: The Mama SASHA experience, 2016-10-20; DVD-1958; Low, Jan
  - Mitochondrial DNA Mutations and Disease: Young and Old, 2016-10-31; DVD-1972; Gu, Zhenglong
    Field of Nutrition Seminar
  - Food Insecurity in the United States in Families with Children, 2016-11-07; DVD-1973; Hanson, Karla
  - Michelle Obama, Food Justice, and the Big Business of Poverty in the South Bronx, 2016-11-10; DVD-1974; Rooks, Noliwe
  - The Implementation Problem in Nutrition through Implementation Science, 2016-11-17; DVD-1975; Pelletier, David
  - Mechanism of RNA Polymerase II Transcriptional Fidelity Control and DNA Modification Recognition, 2016-12-05; DVD-1976; Wang, Dong
  - Polyunsaturated Fatty Acid Biosynthesis, 2017-02-27; DVD-2113; Kothapalli, Kumar
  - Suggested Future Directions, 2017-03-02; DVD-2114; Pinstrup-Andersen, Per
  - Third Trimester Maternal Choline Supplementation Improves Infant Information Processing, 2017-03-06; DVD-2115; Canfield, Richard
  - Qi Sun - Assistant Professor Harvard School of Public Health - "Food Choices as a Key to Cardiometabolic Disease Prevention: the known knowns and the unknown unknowns", 2017-03-20; DVD-2116
  - Using the Lives Saved Tool to model the impact of nutrition intervention scale-up, 2017-02-23; HD-22; Heidkamp, Rebecca
    International Nutrition Seminar NS6980
  - Vitamin A supplementation in the neonatal period: to neonates, or mothers?, 2017-01-27; HD-23; Ross, Catharine
    Pritchard Lecture Series in Human Nutrition
  - Community-based intervention and citizen science approaches for chronic disease prevention among underserved populations: theory, feasibility, and findings, 2016-10-25; HD-24; Seguin, Rebecca
    Special Nutrition seminar
  - Construction of Children's Snacks and Meals in Food Insecure Households: Purpose, Context, and Chaos, 2017-02-02; HD-25; Blake, Christine
    Janet Clay White MS '61 Lecture in Community Nutrition
  - Eric Ravussin, Professor Louisiana State University - "Caloric Restriction: from Clive McCay to CALERIE" - Clive McCay Lectureship, 2017-02-02; HD-26
  - How Nutrition Fuels Human Space Flight, 2017-03-27; DVD-2324; Smith, Scott M.
  - E-Behavioral Nutrition Interventions, 2017-04-10; DVD-2325; Olson, Christine
  - On Iron Biofortification, 2016-11-10; DVD-2326; Haas, Jere
  - High Se Intact on Body Glucose, 2016-11-10; DVD-2327; Lei, Xingen
  - Bangladesh TMRI, 2017-05-08; DVD-2328; Hoddinott, John
  - Sirtuins and Novel PTMs in Cell Signaling and Cancer, 2017-08-28; DVD-2374; Lin, Hening
  - Uncovering the Dark Matter of the Chemistry of Life, 2017-09-18; DVD-2584; Schroeder, Frank
  - Applying Systems Biology to Host-Microbe Interactions in Early Life, 2017-09-25; DVD-2585; Donovan, Sharon
  - Obesity and the Taste System, 2017-10-02; DVD-2586; Dando, Robin
  - Mitochondria: Our Origins-Our Diseases, 2017-10-16; DVD-2587; Wallace, Douglas
  - Mitochondrial Function, Evolution and Diseases, 2017-10-23; DVD-2588; Gu, Zhenglong
  - Stable-Isotopes to Shed Light on Metabolism, 2017-10-24; DVD-2589; Hiller, Karsten
    Special Seminar
  - Multiple Actions of Vitamin D, 2017-10-30; DVD-2590; Christakos, Sylvia
  - Integrating Zinc Biology Into Effective Zinc Interventions, 2017-11-06; DVD-2591; King, Janet
  - Metabolic, Genetic, and Epigenetic Tangles in Folate Dependent 1-C Metabolism, 2017-11-20; DVD-2592; Molloy, Anne
  - Chromatin Regulation, 2017-11-27; DVD-2593; Lee, Sylvia
  - Mechanistic Drivers of the Cardiometabolic Benefits of Bariatric, 2018-02-12; DVD-2628; Cummings, Bethany
  - 2018-01-29, DVD-2629; Azziz, Ricardo
  - Can Microalgae Make Eggs and Chickens Replace Fish?, 2018-02-05; DVD-2630; Lei, Xingen
  - Cysteine Dioxygenase: From Mouse to Molecule to Mouse, 2018-02-26; DVD-2676; Stipanuk, Martha
  - Hypoglycemia and Glucagon Counterregulation, 2018-03-12; DVD-2677; McCall, Anthony
  - The Sphingolipid Ceramide in Humans and Cattle: A Maternal and Pathological Mediator of Insulin Antagonism?, 2018-03-26; DVD-2678; McFadden, Joseph
  - Identifying Genetic and Metabolic Pathways Relating Cardiorespiratory Fitness to Metabolic Health and Longevity, 2018-04-09; DVD-2679; Burant, Charles
  - Gut Microbiota, Diet, Chronic Inflammation, and Metabolic Syndrome, 2018-04-16; DVD-2680; Gewritz, Andrew
  - Diet, Microbiota, and Health: Past, Present and Future, 2018-04-23; DVD-2681; Davis, Cindy
  - A Novel Look at Bile Acids as Regulators of the Neurooendocrine Reproductive Axis, 2018-04-30; DVD-2682; Roberson, Mark
  - Ruminants as Models to Study Endocrine Regulation of Adaptive Metabolism During the Transition from Pregnancy to Lactation, 2018-05-07; DVD-2683; Boisclair, Yves
- Series V. Facilities
  - Savage Hall Building Dedication, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Animal Facility - Space, 1988-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Space Allocation, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Space Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Savage Hall Case Statement, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Mass Spectrometry Lab, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Metabolic Lab - Space Issues, 1983-1995 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Metabolic Lab, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Foods Lab Renovation, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - MVR - Space Issues, 1994-2001 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Savage Hall Dedication, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Savage Hall - Correspondence Concerning Building, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Flora Rose Seminar Room - brochure (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Kinzelberg Hall Dedication, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - DNS Animal Care, 1970-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Series VI. Faculty and Course Syllabi
  - Course Syllabi, 2010; CD-#751
    Fall
  - Nutrition and Disease (NS 441) and Maternal and Child Nutrition (NS 222) syllabi and handouts, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1997-03-1997-06 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1996-12-1997-02 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Publications List, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Memos to Faculty, 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Position in Nutritional Disparities, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - DNS Faculty Meetings, 1988-1996 (Box 7, Folder 6-10)
  - DNS Faculty Meetings - Minutes, 1998-2006 (Box 7, Folder 11-16)
  - DNS Faculty Meetings - DVD #1179, 2012-2013 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - CALS Faculty Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Emeritus Faculty Concerns, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Elliott Blass - Joint Appointment, 1989-1994 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Elliott Blass - Joint Appointment, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Honors, 1985-1996 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Faculty Retreat, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Faculty Retreat, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Human Ecology Faculty Photos, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Inside Information: A Survival Guide for Graduate Studies, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - DNS Faculty Advisor Survival Guide, 2000-2001 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - DNS Faculty Survival Guide, 2002-2003 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - DNS Faculty Survival Guide, 2003-2004 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2006-2007 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2007-2008 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2008-2009 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2011-2012 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2012-2013 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2013-2014 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2014-2015 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2015-2016 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - DNS Survival Guide, 2016-2017 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Faculty Joint Appointments, 1974-1995 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Faculty Policies, 1987-1995 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Membership of Senior Research Associates and TA Recognition Awards, 1988-1995 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Urban Jonsson, 1989-1993 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Bassett Research Institute - Cooperstown, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - J. Gould Schurman Professorship, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Summer Programs in Nutrition, 1991-1996 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Post-Baccalaureate Professional Training, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Nutrition Intervention and Policy (NIP) Position, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - DNS Courses, 1994-1996 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - DNS Field of Nutrition - General, 1995-1996 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Dietetics Position, 1995-2002 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Exercises for Methods in Nutritional Sciences Manual (NS332), 1990 (Box 20, Folder 34-35)
  - Exercises for Methods in Nutritional Sciences Manual (NS332), 1999 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Methods in Nutritional Sciences Anthology (NS332), 1999 (Box 20, Folder 37)
- Series VII. Funding
  - Agreement - Federal Nutrition Lab Research, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Audit Report, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Budget - Conference, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Budget - Conference, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Budget - Conference, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Budget - Conference, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Budget - Conference, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Budget - Conference, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Budget - Conference, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Budget - Conference, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Budget - Conference, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Budget - Conference, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Budget - Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Budget - Conference, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Budget - Conference, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Budget - Hatch, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Budget - Hatch, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Budget - Conference, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Budget - Conference, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Budget - Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Funding Building Mortgage, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Documentary "The China Project on Nutrition, Health, and Environment", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Funding - Alums/Donors, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Hatch Allocations, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Nalith Foundation - Research Funds, 1995-2002 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Nalith Foundation - Research Funds, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Heyward Report, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - MOU between University of Puerto Rico and Cornell, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Funding Need in DNS, 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Borden - Student Support, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Unilever Visit, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Agency for International Development, 1988-1995 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Funding - Thrasher, 1988-1995 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Funding - Nestle, Norwich Eaton, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Pew Charitable Trust, 1990-1994 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Funding Hercules, Inc., 1993-1996 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - UNICEF, 1993-1996 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Rich Foods, 1995-1997 (Box 21, Folder 22)
- Series VIII. Grants and Proposals
  - China Agreement, 1988-1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Res Funds - Equipment, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Heinz Co., 1977-1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - INCAP, Guatemala, 1989-1995 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Grant - Integration of Nutritional Goals and Food Systems, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Kraft Inc., 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - United Nations University - Scrimshaw Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Novel Evaluation of Lactation Performance Grant, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Novel Evaluation of Lactation Performance Grant, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Novel Evaluation of Lactation Performance Grant - Renewal, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Novel Evaluation of Lactation Performance Grant - Renewal, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Nutrition Training Grant Applications, 1982-1989 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Nutrition Training Grant - Summaries of Research, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Nutrition Training Grant Application, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Nutrition Training Grant - Progress Report, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Nutrition Training Grant - Meeting Reports and Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Nutrition Training Grant Applications, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Nutrition Training Grant - Renewal Info, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 30)